<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="console-application">
  <id>io.github.aidarkhusainov.tunwarden</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>TunWarden</name>
  <summary>Linux-first CLI and daemon foundation for Xray-compatible profiles</summary>
  <description>
    <p>TunWarden is a Linux-first command-line client foundation for Xray-compatible profiles. It keeps lifecycle behavior explicit, inspectable, and recoverable while separating user-owned profile intent from daemon and system state.</p>
    <p>The local Debian package installs the CLI, daemon, systemd unit, sysusers configuration, shell completions, manual pages, documentation, and AppStream metadata. Package installation does not start or enable the daemon and does not apply runtime configuration.</p>
  </description>
  <developer id="io.github.aidarkhusainov">
    <name>Aidar Khusainov</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/AidarKhusainov/tunwarden</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/AidarKhusainov/tunwarden/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/AidarKhusainov/tunwarden</url>
  <provides>
    <binary>tunwarden</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="0.0.0~dev" date="2026-06-17">
      <description>
        <p>Development package build with the TunWarden CLI, daemon, systemd unit, sysusers integration, shell completions, manual pages, packaged documentation, and software-center metadata.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Installs TunWarden under Debian and FHS paths without starting or enabling the daemon.</li>
          <li>Includes local package validation gates for binaries, service metadata, shell completions, man pages, AppStream metadata, and package lifecycle checks.</li>
          <li>Keeps generated runtime configuration changes outside package installation.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
